Matthew Irving

Web Developer, SEO Guru, Project Manager

North Lauderdale, FL matthewirving171@yahoo.com (954) 573-4383

Tech visionary with unrivaled ability to turn a client's thoughts and ideas into code. Extensive experience in project management and proficient in HTML, CSS3, JavaScript and Word press development. Also, well versed in Microsoft Office implementations and IT security with advanced Microsoft Excel/Access skills.

Work Experience

Director of Pharmacy Services

US-Rx Care - Tamarac, FL April 2017 to Present

Accomplishments

- Created Microsoft Access based database for storing client savings, generated custom queries and reports to satisfy stakeholder needs
- · Developed Microsoft Excel templates to be use for data analysis, reporting and invoicing
- Implemented electronic faxing to replace paper transmission of correspondence to physician's offices and pharmacies
- Successfully transition all company devices to Microsoft 365
- Designed device security policies and procedures
- Developed operational training manuals and company PTO policy
- Created performance reports that detailed client ROI, cost trends and areas of concern
- Developed COMPTIA Project+, PTCB Certified Pharmacy Technician training programs to assist employees in passing the respective proctored exams

Tasks

- · Creating operational flow for prior authorization process, data analysis and new client on-boarding
- · Developing technical guides for vast array of software programs and operational procedures
- Leading team of pharmacy technicians, pharmacists and other clinical personnel through software and clinical projects
- Selecting, managing and closing projects
- Conducting reviews and providing coaching/training when needed
- · Interviewing and procuring human resources for projects and full/part time employment
- Troubleshooting and resolving computer/network related problems

Freelance Web Developer/Project Manager

Irving Tech Insights - North Lauderdale, FL January 2017 to Present

Accomplishments

• Successfully implemented over 50 Microsoft Office 365 enterprise migrations

- Developed custom Wordpress templates for clients
- Deployed 20+ e-commerce sites using Woocommerce
- Designed promotional images for social media profiles
- Created custom SEO oriented web design methodology designed to maximize website visibility

Tasks

- Developing clientele base through digital and traditional marketing
- Meeting with stakeholders to define web project requirements
- Developing web sites using Word Press and from scratch using HTML, CSS3 and JavaScript
- Remotely installing digital products purchased in company online store
- Providing training and support for Microsoft Office deployments
- Identifying client technological needs and implementing affordable and dependable web based IT solutions
- · Optimizing each URL of client's website to ensure maximum search engine visibility
- Creating content and blog posts for variety of industries
- Providing Microsoft Office training to small businesses
- Consulting businesses on IT security best practices (device hardening, prevention of cross site scripting attacks, responding to denial of service attacks, etc)

Senior Pharmacy Technician

My Favorite Pharmacy - Tamarac, FL December 2014 to April 2017

Accomplishments

- Successfully lead claims processing system migration projects
- Created and implemented customer reward and retention programs
- Developed software/operation guides for pharmacists, technicians and shipping personnel

Tasks

- Managed workflow and medication order fulfillment of 3 full time pharmacy technicians
- Managed pharmacy and technology projects for 3 separate facilities
- Monitored insurance reimbursements and altered purchasing as needed
- Provided monthly reporting to upper management and all pertinent shareholders
- Worked with patients and prescribers to drastically reduce patient out of pocket costs by applying for drug manufacturer's assistance programs

Billing Pharmacy Technician

Pharmacy Holdings USA - Pompano Beach, FL April 2012 to November 2014

Tasks

- Performed root cause analysis of rejected/denied pharmacy claims
- Contacted insurance companies to resolve claim payment issues
- Maintained knowledge base of insurance companies and rates of reimbursement for prescription drug claims
- Transcribed and obtained verbal prescription refill orders from prescribers
- Contacted patients regarding delays in shipments due to various insurance related issues
- Assisted patients/prescribers in obtaining prior authorizations/pre-certifications for specialty/high cost medications

Education

Bachelor's in Information Technology

Fort Lauderdale, FL

Associate in Healthcare Administration

Skills

C#, C++, Html, Javascript, Bootstrap, Php, Scripting, Xml, Css, Search Engine Optimization (5 years), Sql, Hipaa, Deployment, Virtualization, jquery, Pivot tables, Microsoft excel, Adobe (2 years), Project Management (6 years), Wordpress, MYSQL, HTML5, Word Press, CSS3, Website, Word Press

Links

https://www.irvingtechinsights.com

Certifications/Licenses

CompTIA A+

August 2020

CompTIA Network+

August 2020

CompTIA Security+

August 2020

CompTIA Project+

Present

COMPTIA Cloud Essentials

Present

Project Management Professional (PMP)

2022

Certified Pharmacy Technician (CPhT)

2019